<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory.atom"/>
  <title>Lashes By Design - Lash Theory</title>
  <updated>2021-05-31T15:52:28-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lashes By Design</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/do-lash-extensions-damage-your-natural-lashes</id>
    <published>2021-05-31T15:52:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T15:52:28-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/do-lash-extensions-damage-your-natural-lashes"/>
    <title>Do lash extensions damage your natural lashes?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra Welch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>I am sure that you know someone who has had lash extensions and said that they destroyed their natural lashes. In this article, we will go over guiding principals that will ensure that you don’t become that lash artist.</p>
<p>The<span> </span><strong>Golden Rule of Damage-Free lashing</strong><span> </span>is to only adhere to a lash extension that is 2-3 mm longer than your client’s natural lash. Clients will ask you to give them the longest lash that you have. It is important to remember the lash growth cycles as it will help you explain the Golden Rule to your clients. The longer the lash, the more weight it will be and the sooner the lash will fall out. If the lash is too long, it might even break the natural lash.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/do-lash-extensions-damage-your-natural-lashes">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><a name="_Toc73352914"></a>Do lash extensions damage your natural lashes?</p>
<p>What is the Lash Growth Cycle?  </p>
<ul>
<li>Focus on lashing the thin long “teenager” lashes for best retention</li>
<li>Lash “baby lashes” only with very small lashes to fill in gaps</li>
<li>Lash “Adult” lashes last as they will be the first to shed naturally</li>
<li>Lashes DO NOT damage your natural lashes when applied using the “2 mm rule”</li>
</ul>
<p>Natural lashes have three main growth phases, just like all hair on our bodies.  The hair on our head has the same growth phases as our lashes, but the phases are much longer and hair and thus grow much longer!  The lash hair cycle lasts 8 weeks.</p>
<p><strong>Phase 1: Anagen</strong>: We often call these “baby lashes”. They are the new lashes that are extremely fine and short. Often people with significant lash damage from poorly done lash extensions will only have baby lashes because the older lashes were pulled out.</p>
<p><strong>Phase 2: Catagen</strong>: We call these the Teenage lashes. These lashes are long and thin as they mature into adulthood. These are ideal lashes to put lash extensions on since they are firmly rooted and strong. For great lash extension retention, these should be the focus of lashing.</p>
<p><strong>Phase 3: Telogen</strong>: The Telogen lashes are the final stage in hair growth. The lash is mature, long, and thick. As you can see from the diagram, the root is slowly starting to push away from the skin, and it will soon shed. To offer clients a full lash set, these will be important to lash, but they will be the first to shed.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0030/4539/2419/files/Eyelash_growth_phases_480x480.jpg?v=1622482379" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Informed Consent Form for Clients</strong></p>
<p>Most professional lash artists will adhere to the golden rule of lashing, and do no damage, just like doctors vow to do no harm. However, there will be one or two clients that say they don't care about damage. In this case, we recommend creating an Informed Consent Form for clients' to fill in if they want long or heavy lashes that may result in thinning natural lashes. If nothing else, it helps the client fully understand the damage and decide whether they will just go long for special occasions.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/lash-questions-answered</id>
    <published>2021-05-31T13:02:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T15:53:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/lash-questions-answered"/>
    <title>Lash Questions Answered</title>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra Welch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>This series is ideal for anyone who needs a refresher on some topic or perhaps took an online course and didn't catch some of the finer points to lashing. </p>
<p>At Lashes By Design Supply Shop, we hear ALL the real life struggles of lash artists, from beginners to trainers. We love helping other lashers grow and be succcessful. </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/lash-questions-answered">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>We love new lashers! It reminds us of when we first started and thought that learning everything about lashes was going to take FOREVER! Lashing is definitely an art and doing a little extra research will help your new business stand apart. We have compiled a group of topics that lashers ask us when they come into our store today. </p>
<p>This series is ideal for anyone who needs a refresher on some topic or perhaps took an online course and didn't catch some of the finer points to lashing. </p>
<p>At Lashes By Design Supply Shop, we hear ALL the real life struggles of lash artists, from beginners to trainers. We love helping other lashers grow and be successful. </p>
<p><strong>About the Author</strong></p>
<p>Sandra first started getting lashes over 10 years ago and became instantly hooked. After a couple of years she decided to learn how to lash, and within 6 months quit her full time job to lash instead. She not only educated herself on different techniques and materials, she also took 5 more advanced lashing courses to perfect her classic, volume and mega volume techniques. She became an official trainer and distributor and moved out of her front living room into a beautiful Downtown Whitby shop. Within one year, she own product line after working with manufacturers to get the exact products that she wanted. With an eye on product quality, Sandra is always looking for better products to give lashers the tools they need to do their best possible work. </p>
<p>Sandra Welch</p>
<p>Founder and President LBD Boutique Inc.</p>
<p>Master Lasher, Trainer and Business Owner</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/what-is-the-best-lash-adhesive</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T09:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T16:36:02-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/what-is-the-best-lash-adhesive"/>
    <title>What is the Best Lash Adhesive?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra Welch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Which is the best adhesive?</strong></p>
<p>We get asked that every day! The best adhesive is the one that matches<span> </span><strong>your speed</strong><span> </span>of lashing the best. </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.lashesbydesign.ca/blogs/lash-theory/what-is-the-best-lash-adhesive">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Oil Resistant Adhesive? YUP! Its a thing and its in stock! The new formula does not only work in almost all humidity settings, but it is also Oil Resistant to ensure your client's lashes last as long as possible - even in hot humid summers!</p>
<p><br> <strong>FAQ</strong><br> <strong>Which is the best adhesive?</strong></p>
<p>We get asked that every day! The best adhesive is the one that matches <strong>your speed</strong> of lashing the best. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Do you find that you are waiting too long in between each application? Consider choosing a faster adhesive.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Do you find lashes pop off the same day? Your adhesive is too fast and not able to bond to the lash before it starts to dry. Consider a slower adhesive.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Matching Adhesive to Experience Level</strong></p>
<p>Generally, we recommend adhesives based on your experience level as follows:</p>
<p>1) Extra Hold -2 second dry time - ideal for casual or new lashers</p>
<p>2) Mega Hold - 1-second dry time - Most popular and works for the majority of lashers for classic or volume</p>
<p>3) Ultra Hold - .5 second dry time - Only recommended once a lasher finds the Mega Hold is too slow. It is VERY fast. </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Why isn't my adhesive working like it used to?</strong></p>
<p>1) <strong>Manufacturing Date:</strong> The number one reason is the age of the adhesive. At Lashes By Design, we are VERY picky about buying adhesive monthly so that your adhesive is always fresh when you purchase it. As soon as the adhesive is manufactured, it starts to lose its bonding strength. Ask when the adhesive was manufactured if you aren't sure. Every professional lash store should be able to tell you.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pro Tip</strong>: Keep a log of when you opened your adhesive and replenish it monthly even if its not empty. Never buy more than you will need even if it is on sale!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>2) <strong>Weather:</strong> More humidity in the air will always make adhesive dry faster, so consider switching to a slower adhesive during the summer.  I personally alternate between Ultra Hold (Winter) and Mega Hold (Summer). I am pretty casual now so I am probably slower than I used to be too! </p>
<p> </p>
<p>3) <strong>Changes:</strong> If neither of the above are right, then think about what changed in your environment or what products you are using. I always clean the lashes as much as possible to reduce any barrier between the adhesive and the natural lash. Using a gel cleanser or bubble cleanser makes a big difference. I also find primer helps to temporarily dry the lashes and open the hair follicles to make them bond better to adhesive.</p>
<p><br> If All Else Fails... Just ask us! As my favourite trainer used to say, "<strong>There is ALWAYS a reason!"  </strong> We are here to help!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Sandra Welch</strong></p>
<p>Master Lasher and Trainer</p>
<p>Founder of LBD</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
